SLAVA BALYKOV

Carrigtwohill, Co. Cork | (083) 327 0263 | slav.balykov@gmail.com |

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vyacheslav-balykov-pr/ |

Eligible to work in Ireland (Stamp 1G)

SUMMARY

Ambitious and highly skilled PR and Marketing professional with 9 years of extensive experience directing communication and marketing campaigns both agency and in-house settings. Proven success leading corporate marketing and internal communications for companies across diverse industries.

Demonstrated success of developing and implementing media strategies and measuring results across traditional media and digital channels. The portfolio is available by the link.

KEY COMPETENCIES AND SKILLS

- Marketing strategies and campaigns
- Corporate communications
- Internal communications
- Event management
- Sponsorship and Corporate social responsibility
- Research and analysis
- Crisis Communications
- Project management

- Public and Media Relations
- Strategic communications
- Budget planning
- Content development
- Social Media Campaigns
- PR Performance Metrics
- Digital marketing campaigns

EXPERIENCE

National Technological Initiative (NTI) platform, Data-journalism department DATA-JOURNALIST (Contractor), May 2020 – present

Prepare data-driven articles and long reads about new technology markets.

- Held 10 interviews with experts from a scientific, economy and new technology areas;
- Prepared 2 long-reads about new markets development prospects.

ALMALY, LTD - Asset management company

PR MANAGER, June 2019 – November 2019 (quit because of moving to Ireland)

Set up internal and external communication procedures (including crisis communications policy). Coordinated all PR, communication activities inside the group consisting of 43 companies, including pharmaceutical entity, hospitality, QSR (McDonald's), retail, charity, sports, city parking service and gas grid construction, FMCG (mineral water brand).

- Prepared communication plan, aimed to fix parking service company's reputation.
- Implemented PR campaign for a gas supplier, dedicated to launching of gas supply services in the region. After a PR campaign, the number of applications to supplier increased by 30%.
- Media relations. Interacted with local and international media to arrange shareholder's interviews. Negotiate with Time magazine to promote the company's shareholder;
- Successfully prepared and handled internal meeting of the shareholder with top-managers of 43 entities;
- Prepared a wide range of media-releases; public speeches for shareholder and entities' spokespersons; presentations and different type of content for internal and external audiences;
- Managed and approved PR annual budget for all the entities;
- Developed and implement corporate social responsibility projects to draw attention to the Parasport in Kazakhstan.
- Transformed previous archaic website into a modern and functional version.

JÝSAN BANK, JSC – 3rd largest bank in Kazakhstan HEAD OF MARKETING DEPARTMENT, March 2019 — June 2019

Managed all marketing and communications functions overseeing 3M\$ annual budget and 6-member team. Direct internal and external communications, BTL/ATL activities, marketing analytics, digital communications, advertising and branding.

- Successfully provided communication campaigns to a rebranding of Tsesnabank to Jýsan Bank (Zhusan Bank). These campaigns helped to reduce customer's flight by 27% in comparison with the planned index.
- Planned, managed and coordinated marketing department annual and rebranding budget.
- Re-established the marketing department in 2 months;

- Copywriting. Coordinate and edit all outgoing content for internal and external stakeholders;
- Review of public opinion data to analyze sentiment about rebranding;
- Media relations. Spread particular messages in social networks and media resources to maintain the interest to the bank's rebranding

FIRST HEARTLAND BANK, JSC (ex-Royal Bank of Scotland, JSC) – Corporate bank CORPORATE COMMUNICATIONS MANAGER, February 2018 — June 2019

Developed marketing communications activities to attract for B2B clients to the bank. Using the bank history and PR and Marketing tools I maintained FHB's perception as a bank with European values and European doing business style.

By the end of 2018 was chosen as the most "innovative" employee of the bank.

- Successfully conducted all communication activities during the purchase of "Tsesnabank" by First Heartland Bank shareholder.
- Held the international forum dedicated to global development strategy "Belt and Road initiative" in cooperation with the Development Bank of Singapore. More than 150 people from 120 local and international companies participated in the Forum.
- Form and consolidate the bank's corporate culture. Successfully held 7 internal events, including teambuilding's, directorate and corporate events.
- Media relations. Prepared statements and expert commentaries for media. Managed and maintained top-management and shareholder online reputation.
- Copywriting. Served as a primary copywriter for marketing, PR and advertising materials

BURGER KING – Franchisee of Burger King Corp. with 30 restaurants across Kazakhstan.

PR MANAGER, April 2017 — February 2018

Developed and coordinated Burger King Kazakhstan's communication and digital activities. Supervised crisis communications and CSR areas in the company.

- Increased company's share of voice index by 16%, though the establishment of a news buzz and creative activities:
- Created and implemented the Corporate Social responsibility program and launched a
 nationwide CSR project "Whopper 61" with minimum costs and had a great outreach. As a
 result, the planned amount of money was collected in 3 months.
- Coordinated creation of mobile application at all stages from design and copywriting to

launch testing and promotion. We attracted more than 10 000 registered users in 3 months.

- Held 4 online and offline crisis communication trainings for restaurants managers and coordinated 8 mystery shopping tests to assess preparedness to conflicts and crises.
- Media relations and influencers marketing. Using influencer marketing activities we increased Burger King coffee corner customer's income twice.
- Copywriting. Gather research and prepare media releases and articles; approved content for social media pages, creative and advertising materials.
- Coordinated work with digital and PR agencies.
- Planned and managed PR and CSR annual budget.

ALMA TV, LLP – Largest network TV provider in Kazakhstan HEAD OF PR DEPARTMENT, September 2015 — March 2017

Effectively developed and coordinated communication, event and digital marketing activities, including the launch of new products and services and collaboration with international partners.

- Successfully led a crisis communication campaign when more than 500 000 customers
 were cut from the network TV services. Efforts which had been taken helped to maintain a
 client base, despite the crisis, and increase the level of staff loyalty.
- Effectively implemented 24/7 customer support service in social media. It helped to increase the number of official social media pages subscribers by 20%, and reduce the number of calls to call-center by 15%.
- Managed all communication activities during the countrywide prize draw. By the end of the campaign 150 news and articles were published.
- Conducted over 10 events, including press conferences and press previews of new episodes of the "Game of Thrones", "Hurley and the Davidsons" and "Walking Dead" serials.
- Copywriting. Served as a primary copywriter for marketing, PR, advertising materials and also helped with call-center scripts writing;

ART MEDIA, LLP – PR agency

DEPUTY DIRECTOR, January 2014 — September 2015

PR MANAGER, May 2013 — December 2013

Created and distributed news buzz in the interest of the clients. Managed 4-member team.

- Coordinated PR activities regarding the start of SsangYong and Peugeot cars assembly in Kazakhstan. After 6 month campaign over 400 free publications in local and international media.
- Developed and implemented an anti-crisis strategy during the car market crisis in 2014. PR
 and marketing effort helped to decrease customer flight by 15%.
- Oversaw the interaction with 3 huge clients from vehicle, retail and logistic industries.
- Held more than 15 press and blog events for the clients.

INTERFAX KAZAKHSTAN, LLP - International news agency

COMMISSIONING EDITOR, February 2013 — May 2015

Edit and release news in the Interfax Kazakhstan news feeds.

• Led interviews for the agency with local and international celebrities (Michael Madsen, Egor Konchalovskiy and others)

PRESS CENTER SPECIALIST, February 2011 — February 2013

Prepare and organize a wide range of events for media (press tours, press conferences, press lunches, master classes);

- Copywriting. Wrote and edited 70+ press-releases
- Organized and held 35+ press and blog events for local and international clients from different industries.

EDUCATION

SAINT-PETERSBURG SPECIALITY: SOCIO-CULTURAL UNIVERSITY OF THE HUMANITIES ACTIVITY MANAGER

AND SOCIAL SCIENCES (RUSSIA)

Culture Faculty

2004 – 2010

Marketing communications

specialization

CODE INSTITUTE (IRELAND) SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

2020 – present Full-stack software developer

REFRESHER COURSES

International journalism school "MediaNet" (Kazakhstan)

Nazarbayev University (Kazakhstan) 2018

PR, CERTIFICATE (2011) JOURNALISM, CERTIFICATE (2012) CHANGE MANAGEMENT COURSE, CERTIFICATE

PERSONAL

- Strong leader with experience in management;
- Excellent critical thinking, evaluation, analysis, decision making.
- Organized and capable multitasker;
- Outstanding communication skills;
- Comprehensive knowledge of Microsoft applications;
- Attention to details.

LANGUAGE

ENGLISH

RUSSIAN

FLUENT

NATIVE